Fatma Usta

+1 (848) 213-2196 / ustafatma91@gmail.com

I have a valid work permit in Canada

GitHub: fatmausta | LinkedIn: fatmausta

INTRO:

I am currently developing deep learning algorithms with Siemens Healthineers in the USA. I earned my Master's degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering in Canada in 2018. I have 2-year hands-on experience with Python. I am a native speaker of Turkish, and fluent in English (IELTS Academic 7.5/9).

PROFICIENCY:

Python | C++ | Matlab | PyTorch | Keras | Tensorflow | Linux | CUDA cudnn numpy | scikit-image | h5py/HDF5 | Git | GitHub | BitBucket | LaTex

EDUCATION:

MASc. Electrical&Computer Engineering, University of Ottawa, Canada

Sep 2015-Jun 2018

- Conducted research in scar segmentation from 3D LGE-MR images of 34 patients.
- Built solid machine learning and medical image analysis background with Python and Matlab.
- Published two scientific papers as the first author in the SPIE Medical Imaging Conference in 2018.
- Thesis title: Image Processing Methods for Myocardial Scar Analysis from 3D Late-Gadolinium Enhanced Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Images.

BSc. Computer Engineering, Kirikkale University, Turkey

Sep 2009-Jun 2013

- Completed courses; Artificial Intelligence, Image Processing, Advanced Data Structures, Algorithm Design, Object Oriented Programming, Databases, and Web Development.
- ❖ Excelled at scripting with C, C++ and C# for many desktop applications and database systems.

EXPERIENCE:

Deep Learning Research Intern, Siemens Healthineers, Princeton, New Jersey, USA

Mar 2018-Current

- Conducted deep learning research to detect the calcified plaques in coronary arteries from 3D CCTA images of approximately 700 patients.
- ❖ Gained hands-on experience with CNN+LSTM models in Python using PyTorch, Keras and (native) Tensorflow on distributed GPU Clusters in Linux Environment.
- * Experienced working in collaboration with deep learning research teams of over 100 people.

Web-Developer and Database Manager, Kirikkale University Research and Training Sep 2012-Jun 2013 Hospital, Turkey

Developed hospital website using PHP, HTML, and SQL on Oracle database.
 Strengthened the encryption algorithm to encounter attacks to the database.

(1-Year Part-time)

. . .

Software Engineer Intern, JeoIT, Ankara University TechnoCity, Turkey

Jul-Aug 2012

- Scripted a database migration interface to move bug reports to a new program using SQL and C#.
- ❖ Experienced with WCF Web Services, ASP.Net, C#, JQuery, MSSQL, and PL/SQL.

Software Developer Intern, Turkish Telecommunication Company, Ankara, Turkey

Jul-Aug 2011

- Developed a real-time stock automation system accessible from shared networks.
- ❖ Implemented code using Visual Basic(VB), PHP, MySQL, XML, and IIS7.

PUBLICATIONS:

- ❖ F. Usta, W. Gueaieb, J. A. White, C. McKeen, and E. Ukwatta, "Comparison of myocardial scar geometries generated from 2D and 3D LGE MRI," p. 19, Mar. 2018, SPIE, Houston, TX.
- F. Usta, W. Gueaieb, J. A. White, and E. Ukwatta, "3D scar segmentation from LGE-MRI using a continuous max-flow method," p. 29, Mar. 2018, SPIE, Houston, TX.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITY:

- Certificated Cisco CCNA Discovery Network Administrator, 120 hour in-class training in 2012.
- ❖ Guest Lecturer for Engineering Mini Courses Program (EMCP). Taught in an image processing course to over 20 grade-8 students at Carleton University, Canada in May 2017.
- Competed at 3Minute Thesis Competition at the University of Ottawa, Canada in April 2017. Video.
- 2nd Place, Robotic Challenge, Bilkent University Robotic Days in Ankara, Turkey in May 2010.
 I love being active and biking. I have amateur drawings.